Guide to the
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
George and Alexandra Forsythe papers
1936-1979
SC0098
Forsythe, Alexandra I.
Forsythe, George E., (George Elmer), 1917-1972.
40 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. Sandra Forsythe, 1972, and Dianne and Warren Forsythe, 1979.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use.
Biography
Memorial Resolution: George Elmer Forsythe 1917-1972
George E. Forsythe, Professor and Chairman of the Department of Computer Science, died on April 9, 1972, at the age of 55. He founded the Stanford Computer Science Department, one of the first such departments in the nation, on January 1, 1965. His wise counsel, friendly encouragement and inspiring leadership will be sorely missed by his colleagues and his many friends in and outside the department.
George was born on January 8, 1917, in State College, Pennsylvania, and moved as a small boy with his family to Ann Arbor, Michigan. His undergraduate work was at Swarthmore College, where he majored in Mathematics. His experience there had a strong influence on his life. His graduate study was in Mathematics at Brown University where he received his M.S. in 1938 and his Ph.D. in 1941. He then came to Stanford but his first year here was interrupted by service in the Air Force, in which he became a meteorologist. His interest in his fellow students and in education manifested itself very early and he became co-author of an outstanding book on meteorology. Following his service in the Air Force his interest in numerical mathematics and computation developed rapidly. He spent a year at Boeing where he introduced what may have been the first use of automatic computing in that company. He spent several years in the Institute for Numerical Analysis of the National Bureau of Standards, a special section located on the campus of the University of California, Los Angeles. He joined the Institute because he wanted to watch the development of the Standards Western Automatic Computer (SWAC), one of the first of the digital computers. He had many interesting tales to tell of these early days of computing.
Stanford acquired its first computer in 1953, and research and instruction in numerical mathematics and computation began to develop. Soon after this the Mathematics Department began to search for new leadership in this field, and George Forsythe was the unanimous choice of the faculty. It was in 1957 that he returned to Stanford, joining once again the Mathematics Department, this time as Professor. He quickly saw the need for more emphasis on numerical mathematics and computing and was a strong advocate of more involvement in these areas. He was an inspiring and persuasive leader, with an unrivalled sense of timing. He saw the Computer Revolution developing and the need for more study, research, and teaching in the computer area. He conceived it as related to but still different from the traditional emphasis in mathematics; thus, he became convinced of the need for adding scholars well-versed in this area to the faculty. Under his leadership, the Computer Science Division of the Mathematics Department was formed in 1961, and he began the slow process of gathering an outstanding group of colleagues.
The culmination of this effort was the founding of the Computer Science Department on January 1, 1965, by which time he had succeeded in attracting a nucleus of leading computer scientists. Under his dynamic leadership and foresight the department developed into one of the outstanding Computer Science Departments in the nation. George was very skillful in bringing together many diverse points of view. He captured the loyalty of his colleagues. He was a master at resolving differences between people with different views. Of all his professional activities, building and leading the department was closest to his heart. He did, however, contribute his leadership to Stanford in other but related tasks. He served as Director of the Stanford Computation Center from 1961 to 1965. He played a major role insuring effective interaction between the University and the distinguished computer experts from education, government, and industry on the Computer Science Advisory Committee. During his last two years he was chairman of the Presidential Committee on Computation Facilities and the leading voice in urging that greater attention be given to effective use of computers at Stanford.
George had a nationwide influence on Computer Science education. The emergence of a discipline of Computer Science is due to his efforts more than to those of any other single person. As editor of the Algorithms Department of the Communications of the Association for Computing Machinery, a prominent journal, he made important contributions to the quality of technical computer science publications. He served a term as President of the Association for Computing Machinery from 1964 to 1966. His influence on computer education and other activities in the computer area continued long after his term of office was ended.
In his research, lectures, and publications, he tried to serve as the mediator between the theoretical mathematician, the application-minded engineer and the numerical analyst who had to cooperate with both and had to utilize their knowledge and experience in order to help them in solving their problems. He was the author of two books in this vein: Finite-Difference Methods for Partial Differential Equations (with Wolfgang Wasow), John Wiley, New York, 1960, and Computer Solution of Linear Algebraic Systems (with Cleve B. Moler), Prentice-Hall, New Jersey, 1967. Both of these books have been translated into Russian and Japanese and the latter one also into German. His judgments on the practical possibilities and potentials of theoretical procedures in mathematics were highly appreciated by his colleagues in pure mathematics and his criticism was always stimulating and helpful.
George was always most concerned with students' welfare, making all of his vast library of books and reprints freely available to them as well as to his colleagues. In any discussion with his colleagues he was a strong advocate of what he felt would most benefit the students. Their progress and development were his constant concern. Perhaps the most visible and enduring evidence of his influence on other people is to be seen in the significant contributions that have been made and are being made by the students whose research he guided. He was never too busy to see and encourage them, and he chose their problems wisely. He instilled in them a fine feeling for the techniques of research so that most of them have continued to work in important areas. The influence of his students on the direction of research in numerical analysis and on the development of computer science has been remarkable.
He enjoyed an active life, continuing to play tennis until only a few weeks before his death. He was also a jogger and a hiker. He loved the out-of-doors. He and his wife, Sandra, were married on the same day that he received his Ph.D. She shared his interest in computation and shared with him early experiences in using SWAC. While George was developing Computer Science education at the college level, Sandra was also actively pioneering this area at the high school level and continues to pursue this activity. Together they enjoyed travelling in many countries and hiking in the High Sierras. In addition to his wife, George is survived by his son Warren (Tuck), who is a graduate student of botany at the University of Montana, and by his daughter, Diana, a graduate student of anthropology at Cornell.
John G. Herriot, Chairman
Gene H. Golub
Donald E. Knuth
William F. Miller
Menahem M. Schiffer
Scope and Content
The papers of George and Alexandra Forsythe include professional correspondence, notes for lectures and publications, committee records and publications, materials relating to the Forsythes' writings in the field of computer science, and materials relating to Alexandra Forsythe's interest in secondary school instruction of computer science.
Access Terms
Association for Computing Machinery..; Dantzig, George Bernard, 1914-2005.; Forsythe, Alexandra I.; Forsythe, George E., (George Elmer), 1917-1972.; George, Alan.; Hamming, R. W., (Richard Wesley), 1915-1998.; Hockney, Roger W.; Lyman, Richard W., 1923-2012.; O'Flaherty, Michael.; Pólya, George,, 1887-1985.; Stanford University. Computer Science Department.; Stanford University. Department of Mathematics.; Suppes, Patrick, -1922; Terman, Frederick Emmons, 1900-1982; Computer science--Study and teaching; Computer science.; Computer scientists--California.; Mathematics--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- George Forsythe Papers, 1938-1972; Series 1
  - AAAS (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AAUP (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Academic Council (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Acceleration of Convergence (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ACM (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ACM - Council (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ACM - Curriculum (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ACM - Education Board (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ACM - Goals (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - ACM - Newsletters (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ACM - Personal (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ACM - SICCSE (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - ACM - SIGNUM (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Advisory Committee, Oct 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Advisory Committee, Apr 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Advisory Committee, Oct 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Advisory Committee, Apr 1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Advisory Committee, Jan 1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Advisory Committee, Oct 1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Airspeed and Related Computers (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Algebra, Not Matrices (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Algebraic Equations, Solutions of (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Algebraic Systems, Nonlinear (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Algebraic Systems, Quadratic (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Algol Notes (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Algol W (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Algol Working Group (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Education (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American Mathematical Society (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Analogue Computers (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Analogue Experiments (Box 2, Folder 4a)
  - Anthropology (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Approximation and Smoothing of Functions (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Approximation of Numbers (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Argonne National Laboratories (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Artificial Intelligence (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - ARPA (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Baker, Billy (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Barry, Jeanne (Separation of Exponentials) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bell Telephone Laboratories Library (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bibliographies (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bit-Dropper Puzzle (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Biographies (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Blue-Sky Ideas (Variety of possible uses of computers) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Boeing Notes (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Bowker, Dean A.H. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Braden (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - British Computer Society (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cahil, Dolly (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Calculus and Computing (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Calculus of Variations (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Calendars (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Card - Matching (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Card - Stunts (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Causey (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Ceeb (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Chebyshev Polynomials (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Chemistry (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Classification (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Climatology (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Cole, R. Wade (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Combinatorial Math (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Committee on University Policy (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Communications in Mathematical Sciences (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Compiler Theory (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Computation Center (Box 2, Folder 38a)
  - Computation Center Network (Box 2, Folder 38b)
  - Computation Research Labs (Box 2, Folder 38c)
  - Computer Assisted Instruction (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - CS239 - Students (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - CS239 - Abbott--Pendray (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - CS239 - Cejalvo (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - CS239 - Duke (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - CS239 - Lindquist (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - CS239 - Lord (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - CS239 - Maaz (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - CS239 - Robertson (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - CS239 - Therbault (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Computer Science Education - Hammer (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Computer Science - Graduate Departments (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - CS-Other Universities - General (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - CS-Other Universities - Arizona (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - CS-Other Universities - Australia (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - CS-Other Universities - Berkeley (U.C.) (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - CS-Other Universities - Brown (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - CS-Other Universities - Univ. of Calif. - Irvine (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - CS-Other Universities - Univ. of Calif. - Santa Cruz (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - CS-Other Universities - Calif. Tech. - Pasadena (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - CS-Other Universities - California - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - CS-Other Universities - Carnegie Tech. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - CS-Other Universities - Canada (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - CS-Other Universities - Colorado (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - CS-Other Universities - Connecticut (Yale) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - CS-Other Universities - Cornell (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - CS-Other Universities - England (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - CS-Other Universities - Europe (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - CS-Other Universities - Florida (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - CS-Other Universities - Georgia (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - CS-Other Universities - Hawaii (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - CS-Other Universities - Illinois (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - CS-Other Universities - Indiana (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - CS-Other Universities - Iowa (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - CS-Other Universities - Kansas (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - CS--Other Universities - Maryland (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - CS--Other Universities - Massachusetts (MIT) (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - CS--Other Universities - Massachusetts (Harvard) (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - CS--Other Universities - Michigan (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - CS--Other Universities - Minnesota (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - CS--Other Universities - Miscel. Foreign Universities (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - CS--Other Universities - Missouri (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - CS--Other Universities - Miscel. Universities (U. S.) (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - CS--Other Universities - Nebraska (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - CS--Other Universities - Nevada (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - CS--Other Universities - New Hampshire (Dartmouth) (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - CS--Other Universities - New Jersey (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - CS--Other Universities - New Mexico (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - CS--Other Universities - New York (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - CS--Other Universities - North Carolina (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - CS--Other Universities - Ohio (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - CS--Other Universities - Oklahoma (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - CS--Other Universities - Oregon (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - CS--Other Universities - Pennsylvania (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - CS--Other Universities - Princeton (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - CS--Other Universities - Puerto Rico (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - CS--Other Universities - Tennessee (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - CS--Other Universities - Texas (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - CS--Other Universities - Virginia (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - CS--Other Universities - Washington (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - CS--Other Universities - Wisconsin (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - CS--Other Universities - Utah (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - COSRIMS (Box 4, Folder 13a)
  - Computer Systems Design (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Computing Reviews (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Conference Board of the Mathematical Sciences (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Conformal Mapping (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Continued Fractions (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Control Theory (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - COSINE (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - COSRIMS (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - COSRIMS Graduate Education Panel (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Cottrell, Ann (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - CUPM (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Curiosae (pi and other things) (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Customer Relations (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Cuykendall (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Daniel, Jim (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Dantzig, George (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Delp (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Determinant (Average Value)--Distribution of Eigenvalues (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Differential Analyzer (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Digital Computer Uses - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Discrete Variables (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Dresden Seminar (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Dutrow, Sam (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Economics (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Education--Applied Math (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Education--College Math, Curriculum Revision (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Education--High School--Problems (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Education--Junior High School--Lectures (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Education--Math Exams (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Education--Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Education--Numerical Analysis (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Education--Numerical Analysis, Standard Courses (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Education--NA NDEA Title IV (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Education--Palo Alto (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Education--Seminar Areas (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Eigenvalues of Operators (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Elasticity (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Factor Analysis (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Club (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Fast Fourier Transformation (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Feller--Forsythe (s > 1) (matrix transformation) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Feigenbaum (Box 5, Folder 10a)
  - Fein,L. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fellowships (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Film Catalogues (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - FJCC, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Floyd (Box 5, Folder 14a)
  - Fluid Dynamics (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Flutter Analysis (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Focus (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Formula Collection (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Forsysthe Talks (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Forsythe Lectures--2 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Forsythe My Day Letters (as president of ACM) (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Forsythe Lecture on Pitfalls (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Forsythe Transparencies for Pitfall Lecture (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Forsythe-Lee (Variational Study of Nonlinear Spline Curves) (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Forsythe and Moler-- Computer Study of Nonlinear Spline Curves (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Forsythe Talks--NA--High School (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Forsythe Talks--Education (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - FORTRAN (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Freshmen (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Games Theory (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Gatlingburg Papers (matrix symposia), 1961 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Gatlingburg Papers, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Gatlingburg Papers, April 1969 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Geometry (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - George, Alan (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Gibb, A. (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Gilbarg (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Dr Good Paper (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Golub--Forsythe (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Grace, Donald (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Grad Study Committee (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Gragg (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Graph Theory (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Green, Mike (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Hamming, R.W. (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Hawaii (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Heffner (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Hilbert Data (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Hilbert Matrices (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Hilbert Space - CG Method (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - History of Computing (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hockney, Roger (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Homework 10ff (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Humanities (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Humanities and Sciences Faculty (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Hydrodynamics (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - IEEE Computer Group (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - IBM (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - IFIP (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - India (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Information Retrieval (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Information Theory (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Institute for Numerical Analysis (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Integral Equations (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Integration, Numerical (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - International Computing Center (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - International Congress of Mathematicians, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Interpolation (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Interviews (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Jackson (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Job Control Language (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Kaufman (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Key Punching (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Kurtz (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - L-shapes (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Law (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Leonard Paper (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Levine, David (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Levy, John (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Library (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Library--Classification (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Library--Ad Hoc (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Library--Computer Science Branch (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Linear Equations (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Linear Equations--Hold (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Linear Inequalities (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Linear Programs (and Nonlinear) (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Linguistics (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Lipkis, Jim (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - List Processing (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Lockheed (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Logics of Circuitry (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Logic and Logic of Programming (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Lyman (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Madison, April 1965 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Maps (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Marchant Computing Aids (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Master of Science in Computer Science (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Master's Theses (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Math Offprint Service (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Math 10 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Math 10ff--Masters (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Math 110C (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Math 114 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Math 115 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Math 135 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Math 136 S. U. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Math 136 U.C.L.A. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Math 136 1952 Notes (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Math 139 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Math 139 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Math 251 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Math 252 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Math Association of America (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Math Dept. - Comprehensive Exams (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Math Dept. Meetings (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Mathematical Assistants (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Math Exams (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Math Program Library (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Math Reviews (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Math Science Curriculum (Terman Committee) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Matrices--Bellman (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Matrices--Gatlingburg, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Matrices--Golub (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Matrices--Madison (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Matrix Condition--Young (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Matrix Inversion - Finite Iterations CG (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Matrix Inversion - Iterations (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Matrix Inversion - - Gradient (with Motzkin) (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Matrix Inversion - Elimination and Orthoganalization (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Matrix Inversion - Special Methods and Machines (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Matrix Inversion - Overall and Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Matrix Inversion - Tapes (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Matrix Inversion - Errors (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Matrix Inversion - Monte Carlo (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Matrix Inversion - Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Matrix Inversion - Book Material (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Matrix - Lewy (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Matrix Matters - Young (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Chap 0 (apparently notes for an unfinished book on matrices) (Box 7, Folder 34)
    According to Alexandra Forsythe, these chapters were probably for the book Dr. Forsythe was writing with Michael Malcolm. It was finished by Cleve Moler and Michael Malcolm and published by Prentiss Hall.
  - Chap 1 (empty) (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Chap 2 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Chap 3 (Folder 37)
  - Chap 4 (Folder 38)
  - Chap 5 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Chap 6 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Chap 7 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Chap 8 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Chap 9 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Chap 10 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Chap 11 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Chap 12 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Chap 13 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Matrix Spectrometer (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Matrix Problems (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Matrix Eigenvalue - Frame - SWAC (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Matrix Book Material, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Matrix - ADCM Codes (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Matrices - Wilkenson and Givens (Box 7, Folder 53)